Finding Aid for the Edward Ross Roybal Papers LSC.0847
UCLA Library Special Collections
Edward Ross Roybal papers
1947-1962
UCLA Library Special Collections
Roybal, Edward Ross
LSC.0847
18.4 linear feet (45 document boxes and 1 flat box)
Edward Ross Roybal (1916- ) was a public health educator for the California Tuberculosis Association (1942-44), the director of health education for the Los Angeles County Tuberculosis and Health Association (1945-49), a member of the Los Angeles City Council (1949-62), president of Eastland Savings and Loan Association (1958-68), and a Democrat in the U.S. Congress, House of Representatives (1963-93) where he served as chairman of the Select Committee on Aging from 1989-93. The collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, notes, photographs, and printed material related to his career as a Los Angeles City Councilman.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edward Ross Roybal, 1963.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9964213383606533
Biography/History
Edward Ross Roybal was born into a family that traced its roots to Spain's colonization of northern New Mexico in 1598. In 1922, a railroad strike prevented his father from being able to work, and Roybal moved with his family to the East Los Angeles neighborhood of Boyle Heights, where he attended local public schools, graduating from Roosevelt High School in 1934. After graduation, Roybal joined the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), a New Deal program that provided him with an experience that both reflected and reinforced his developing commitment to public service. After serving in the CCC, Roybal attended the University of California, Los Angeles, and later studied law at Southwestern University.
In 1942 Roybal began work as a public health educator with the California Tuberculosis Association. His work there, however, was interrupted by a tour in the Army where he worked as an accountant for an infantry unit. Upon returning home, he began work as director of health education for the Los Angeles County Tuberculosis and Health Association, a position he held until 1949.
In 1947, having been encouraged by many familiar with his work in social outreach programs on Los Angeles' east side, Roybal decided to run for the 9th District Seat of the Los Angeles City Council, then held by Parley Parker Christensen. The district, which included Boyle Heights, Bunker Hill, Civic Center, Chinatown, Little Tokyo, and the Central Avenue corridor, was then 45% White, 34% Latino, 15% African American, and 6% "other." Roybal, unable to secure a large enough portion of the vote from outside the Latino community to overcome Christianson's support across ethnic lines and from organized labor in particular, lost the election.
In 1949, Roybal teamed with local organizer Fred Ross and a group of people who had supported his earlier campaign to form the Community Service Organization (CSO), one of the first coalition building organizations in Los Angeles, CA which tied together a variety of religious, political, racial, ethic, and organized labor groups to fight local discrimination. The organization, which organized get-out-the-vote drives, did not explicitly endorse candidates but Roybal's presence as president of the organization and the personal endorsements of many of its members helped garner a swell of support that contributed to Roybal's victory.
Taking office in 1949, Roybal began a long career in public office; he served as a councilman from 1949 to 1962 and was president pro-tempore in his last term. As councilman, he became a figure of great importance, particularly on issues confronting the local Latino community. Most famously, he led the opposition the land swap taken under eminent domain by the city of Los Angeles, and then given to private enterprise, that allowed for Dodger Stadium to be built in the largely Mexican-American community of Chavez Ravine.
During his time within the City Council, Roybal, as a prominent young Democrat, received encouragement to run for higher office. In 1954, he lost an effort to become Lieutenant Governor, although he still received more votes than the Democratic candidate for Governor. Running in 1958 against Ernest Debs for a seat on the Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors, Roybal lost a bitterly-contested election in which he held a slim lead on election night, but lost after four recounts gave the election to Debs, fueling suspicions of voter fraud. Despite this, Roybal ran for Congress in 1962, winning the election in the 25th District – an area that included his native Boyle Heights, East Los Angeles, Downtown, and parts of Hollywood. After his departure, the City Council went 23 years without a Latino member until Richard Alatorre's election in 1985.
Beginning his term in 1963, he became the first Latino Congressperson from California since the 1878 election of Romualdo Pacheco. As Congressman, Roybal was generally known for a low-key legislative style. In his first term, he served on the Interior and Insular Affairs Committee and the Post Office Committee. In his next term, he served on the Foreign Affairs Committee and on the Veteran's Affairs Committee. Beginning in 1971, he served on the House Appropriations Committee for more than two decades and authored a number of bills, many of which were not universally popular, that offered support for groups he saw as disenfranchised. Many of his actions were on behalf of veterans, the elderly, and Mexican-Americans.
He was also critical of the House Un-American Activities Committee and the politics of McCarthyism, and was the sole vote against the Subversive Registration Bill, which required written loyalty oaths. Several sections of the bill were were later ruled unconstitutional by the United States Supreme Court. In 1960 Roybal helped organize the Mexican American Political Association (MAPA) and served as its first president from 1960 to 1962.
In 1967 he wrote the first bill giving federal support to bilingual education, creating specialized language instruction for immigrant populations. As Chairman of the House Select Committee on Aging, he led a successful campaign to restore $15 million in funding for low-cost health programs and expanded public housing for senior citizens. In 1982 he worked to preserve the Meals on Wheels program and veterans' preferences in hiring. In the early 1980s, against the wishes of many of his own constituents, he argued for expanded funding for AIDS research.
In 1976 he became a founder of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus (CHC) and later co-founded the National Association of Latino Elected and Appointed Officials (NALEO). In 1986, as chair of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus, he led the unsuccessful opposition to the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, also known as the Simpson-Mazzoli Act.
Roybal retired in 1993 after thirty years in office. That year, following redistricting, his daughter Lucille Roybal-Allard became the Representative for the 33rd District, which contained part of Roybal's district; while Xavier Becerra, with Roybal's endorsement, won the election in the 30th District, which included much of the remaining territory of Roybal's former 25th District.
At the time of his death, more buildings in Los Angeles and in the nation were named after him than any other single person. Among the buildings named for Roybal are the Edward R. Roybal Federal Building located in what had been his home district in California, the Edward R. Roybal Comprehensive Health Clinic in East Los Angeles, the Edward R. Roybal Learning Center, the University of Southern California Edward R. Roybal Institute on Aging, the main campus of the Center for Disease Control in Atlanta, Georgia, and thirteen federally funded Roybal Centers for Health Promotion and Translation located on various university campuses throughout the United States.
Congressman Roybal credited many of his accomplishments to the enduring love and support of his life-long partner of 65 years, Lucille Beserra Roybal. After retiring from Congress, he founded the Lucille and Edward Roybal Foundation which awards scholarships to Latino and Latina students pursuing careers in the field of health. Edward Roybal lived the rest of his life in Pasadena, California with his wife Lucille, as one of the deans of local and national politics, endorsing several candidates in elections throughout the region. He died at the age of 89 at the Huntington Hospital in Pasadena of respiratory failure complicated by pneumonia.
Scope and Content
Collection contains a variety of documents related to the work of Edward Ross Roybal as a member of the Los Angeles City Council from 1949-1962 and as a member of multiple organizations and commissions during his tenure. Materials include correspondence, propaganda booklets and pamphlets, magazine and newspaper clippings, photographs, reports, maps, blueprints, radio broadcasts, and various Los Angeles City Council documents produced during this period. Notable peer correspondence includes former Governor Edmund G. Brown, former representative Clair Engle, and former supervisor John Anson Ford. Many documents concern developments and improvements including Boyle Heights, Bunker Hill, Chavez Ravine, downtown Los Angeles, general infrastructure improvements, the Los Angeles International Airport, the Los Angeles Zoo and Botanical Gardens, the Los Angeles freeway system, and oil drilling locations. The variety of positions taken towards these developments by Roybal's constituents, peers, affiliated organizations, and non-affiliated organizations can be found within the documents (specifically correspondence, propaganda, and newspaper clippings). Groups in which Roybal was active include the American Legion, the Boy Scouts, the Council for Equality in Employment, the Eastland Savings and Loan Association, the Mexican American Political Association (MAPA), and the Welfare Council of Metropolitan Los Angeles. Extensive correspondence with non-affiliated organizations and bodies exists between Roybal and the Downtown Business Men's Association, the Los Angeles Housing Authority, the Los Angeles Police Department, and the League of Women Voters of Los Angeles. Additionally, the collection contains documents on the creation of ordinances regarding environmental, health, and societal issues facing Los Angeles during this period. These include air pollution, discriminatory housing practices, juvenile delinquency, public health services, public transportation, rabies vaccination, segregation, traffic, unemployment, and race relations (primarily Latin American, yet also including African American, Chinese American, Japanese American, and Jewish American). The collection also includes material on external relations and events concerning Los Angeles, with notable cases being Latin American affairs, sisters cities in Japan and Mexico, anti-Communist campaigns, and Civil Defense documents produced on the eve of the Cuban Missile Crisis.
Organization and Arrangement
Collection arranged alphabetically by subject. As the collection was processed the original alphabetical organizational structure was maintained according to subject. Minimal adjustments were made only when a document was clearly misfiled. This gives insight into Roybal's documentation of historical events and municipal developments in Los Angeles following World War II. Researchers should not that although explicit subject files exist for many of Roybal's peers and affiliated organizations, documents produced by them may also be filed under a variety of other related subjects.
Related Material
Edward R. Roybal papers, 1919-2003 (Collection 107). Available at the UCLA Chicano Studies Research Center Library.
Knox Mellon, Jr. Collection of California Democratic Council Papers (Collection 1061). Available at Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Online items available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online through Calisphere: Roybal (Edward R.) papers (123 items)
Los Angeles (Calif.). City Council.; Photographs.; Los Angeles (Calif.) -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Mexican American legislators -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Los Angeles (Calif.). Police Department.; California. State Fair Employment Practice Commission.; Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-1996 --Correspondence. -- Correspondence; Engle, Clair, 1911-1964 --Correspondence. -- Correspondence; Ford, John Anson--Correspondence. -- Correspondence; Housing Authority of the City of Los Angeles, California; Ford, John Anson; League of Women Voters of Los Angeles; Mexican American Political Association (Calif.); Roybal, Edward Ross -- Archives
- A., 1950-1959. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adoptions, Bureau of., 1957-1958. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adult Authority., 1955-1962. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Air Pollution (1 of 2)., 1958-1960. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Air Pollution (2 of 2)., 1952-1955. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Airports Dept., 1955-1962. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alcoholic Beverages Control., 1949-1959. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alcoholism (1 of 2)., 1951-1957. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Alcoholism (2 of 2)., 1949-1962. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- All City Employees Association (1 of 2)., 1960-1962. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- All City Employees Association (2 of 2)., 1956-1959. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- All Nations Foundation., 1961-1962. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Aliso Village Nursery School., 1960. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- American Civil Liberties., 1949-1957. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- American Federation of Labor., 1958-1959. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- American Legion., 1958-1959. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Animal Regulation (1 of 3)., 1950-1956. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Animal Regulation (2 of 3)., 1957-1959. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Animal Regulation (3 of 3)., 1960-1962. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Animal Regulation Complaints., 1952-1962. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Annexations., 1957-1958. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Anti-Vivisection., 1947-1950. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Armed Forces Matters., 1960-1961. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Army and Navy Matters., 1950-1959. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Art Commission., 1951-1957. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Art Dept., 1959-1962. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Assistance, Bureau of., 1959-1962. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- B., 1953-1962. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Big Brothers, East L.A., 1958-1961. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bill of Rights., 1949-1961. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Blind, Committee for., 1957-1960. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Boyle Heights Improvement., 1961. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Boys Groups., 1957-1962. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Bridge Design., 1949-1956. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Brown, Governor Edmund G. "Pat" (1 of 2)., 1958-1959. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Brown, Governor Edmund G. "Pat" (2 of 2)., 1959-1962. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Budget., 1958-1959. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Building and Safety (1 of 2)., 1951-1958. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Building and Safety (2 of 2)., 1959-1962. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Building and Safety (Complaints)., 1956-1962. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Building Rehabilitation., 1957-1958. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Bunker Hill (1 of 5)., 1949-1959. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bunker Hill (2 of 5)., 1951-1958. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Bunker Hill (3 of 5)., 1955-1959. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Bunker Hill (4 of 5)., 1958. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bunker Hill (5 of 5)., 1954-1962. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- C., 1956-1962. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Capital Improvement Program., 1957-1962. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Castro Fund, Armando (1 of 2)., 1954-1959. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Castro Fund, Armando (2 of 2)., 1955-1959. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Catholic Welfare., 1949-1962. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Census., 1950-1960. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Chamber of Commerce (1 of 2)., 1957-1958. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Chamber of Commerce (2 of 2)., 1957-1962. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Chavez Ravine (1 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Chavez Ravine (2 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Chavez Ravine (3 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Chavez Ravine (4 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Chavez Ravine (5 of 13)., 1954-1959. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Chavez Ravine (6 of 13)., 1957-1962. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Chavez Ravine (7 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Chavez Ravine (8 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Chavez Ravine (9 of 13)., 1957-1959. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Chavez Ravine (10 of 13)., 1959-1962. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Chavez Ravine (11 of 13)., 1957-1962. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Chavez Ravine (12 of 13)., 1958-1960. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Chavez Ravine (13 of 13)., 1958-1959. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Chavez Ravine and Dodger Stadium (Newspaper Clippings)., 1958-1962. (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Chavez Ravine and Dodger Stadium (Promotional material and site maps) (Box 46, Folder 2)
- Chinese Matters., 1960-1962. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Christmas Greetings., 1957-1958. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Citizenship., 1960-1962. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- City Attorney., 1954-1962. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- City Council., 1957-1962. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Civic Center., 1959-1962. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Civil Defense (1 of 3)., 1957-1959. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Civil Defense (2 of 3)., 1959-1962. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Civil Defense (3 of 3)., 1958-1960. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Civil Rights., 1955-1961. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Civil Service Department., 1954-1961. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Clean Up Campaign., 1960. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Coliseum, Memorial., 1957. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Communism., 1950-1961. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Community Chest., 1960-1962. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Community Redevelopment., 1960-1962. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Community Relations., 1949-1960. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Community Service Org. (1 of 3)., 1959-1961. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Community Service Org. (2 of 3)., 1949-1957. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Community Service Org. (3 of 3)., 1957-1959. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Conference, Christians and Jews., 1955. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Condolences., 1949-1962. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Congratulations (1 of 2)., 1957-1962. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Congratulations (2 of 2)., 1949-1959. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Contributions., 1951-1962. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Country Matters., 1957-1959. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Crime and Horror Books., 1954. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Crossing Guard., 1949-1957. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- D., 1957-1962. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Democratic Clubs, etc. (1 of 2)., 1957-1962. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Democratic Clubs, etc. (2 of 2)., 1953-1957. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Discrimination., 1950-1960. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- District Matters., 1949-1960. (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Dump Sites., 1953-1958. (Box 9, Folder 15)
- E., 1954-1962. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- East Central Area Welfare Planning Committee., 1960-1962. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Eastland Savings and Loan Association., 1958-1962. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Eastside Boys Club., 1958-1962. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Eastside Settlement House., 1959-1960. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Education, Department of., 1953-1962. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Employment., 1949-1962. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Engineering Bureau., 1951-1961. (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Engineers and Architects., 1957-1960. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Equal Employment, President's Committee., 1962. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- F., 1956-1962. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Fair Employment Practice Commission (1 of 3)., 1952-1959. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Fair Employment Practice Commission (2 of 3)., 1957-1962. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Fair Employment Practice Commission (3 of 3)., 1949-1957. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Fire and Police Protective League., 1958-1962. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Fire Department., 1949-1961. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Fire Department (Complaints)., 1953-1962. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Firearms., 1959. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Ford, Supervisor John Anson., 1950-1958. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Foreign Visitors., 1962. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Foundations., 1956-1962. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Fourth Street Project., 1951-1955. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Freeways., 1954-1962. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Freeways, 9th District., 1949-1962. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Friendship Day Camp., 1953-1962. (Box 12, Folder 4)
- G., 1954-1962. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Garbage Collection., 1951-1954. (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Get Well Messages., 1962. (Box 12, Folder 7)
- H., 1957-1962. (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Handicapped People., 1956-1962. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Harbor Department., 1956-1962. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Health and Welfare (1 of 3)., 1954-1956. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Health and Welfare (2 of 3)., 1958-1962. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Health and Welfare (3 of 3)., 1957-1962. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Health Center, Northeast., 1955-1962. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Health Department (1 of 3)., 1959-1962. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Health Department (2 of 3)., 1957-1959. (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Health Department (3 of 3)., 1952-1957. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Health Department Complaints., 1950-1962. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Henderson Community Center., 1955-1957. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Holy Family Adoption (1 of 2)., 1957-1959. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Holy Family Adoption (2 of 2)., 1951-1962. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Housing (1 of 5)., 1957-1959. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Housing (2 of 5)., 1949-1957. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Housing (3 of 5)., 1959-1962. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Housing (4 of 5)., 1962. (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Housing (5 of 5)., 1949-1953. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- I., 1957-1962. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Immigration and Naturalization., 1950-1954. (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Immigration Matters., 1951-1962. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Immigration, Museum of., 1956. (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Improvements, In District (1 of 2)., 1957-1960. (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Improvements, In District (2 of 2)., 1957-1961. (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Improvements, Rec and Parks., 1959. (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Improvements, Street Design., 1952-1957. (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Incineration., 1953-1955. (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Industry and Transportation., 1952-1961. (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Inspection Division., 1953-1957. (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Inter American Advisory Board., 1959-1961. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Introductions., 1952-1962. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Invitations (1 of 11)., 1957-1959. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Invitations (2 of 11)., 1959-1962. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Invitations (3 of 11)., 1961-1962. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Invitations (4 of 11)., 1951-1962. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Invitations (5 of 11)., 1960-1961. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Invitations (6 of 11)., 1961-1962. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Invitations (7 of 11)., 1961. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Invitations (8 of 11)., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Invitations (9 of 11)., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Invitations (10 of 11)., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Invitations (11 of 11)., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 7)
- J., 1958-1961. (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Japanese Organizations., 1954-1962. (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Jewish Organizations (1 of 2)., 1956-1959. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Jewish Organizations (2 of 2)., 1960-1962. (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Jury., 1957-1961. (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Juvenile Delinquency., 1950-1962. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Juvenile Hall., 1948-1950. (Box 18, Folder 6)
- K., 1952-1962. (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Kennedy, President John F., 1959-1962. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- L., 1958-1962. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Landmarks., 1954-1961. (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Latin American Affairs (1 of 2)., 1961-1962. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Latin American Affairs (2 of 2)., 1958-1962. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Latin American, Education of (1 of 2)., 1954-1959. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Latin American, Education of (2 of 2)., 1959-1960. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Latin American, General (1 of 2)., 1952-1957. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Latin American, General (2 of 2)., 1957-1959. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- League of California Cities., 1961-1962. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- League of Women Voters., 1960-1962. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Library Department., 1950-1962. (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Lobbyists., 1962. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Loma Linda University., 1961-1962. (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Los Angeles Beautiful., 1957-1962. (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Lot Cleaning., 1953-1962. (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Loyalty Checks., 1948-1951. (Box 20, Folder 6)
- M., 1954-1962. (Box 20, Folder 7)